It's great to have you back.
In the final exercise at the last lesson you
integrated everything you've learned so far into an Edge Application.
That app switched us from just images to using
videos as well as creating an output video.
However, what about using Webcam inputs,
or instead streaming information,
or the output video itself somewhere over the Internet.
In this lesson, we'll cover some crucial topics to do
so including some more basics of OpenCV,
handling input streams in OpenCV,
processing model outputs for additional useful information,
the basics of MQTT,
and its use with Internet of Things devices,
sending statistics and video streams to a server, performance basics,
and then we'll finish up by thinking about
additional model use cases as well as some end user needs. Let's get started.