So far I've mentioned node servers a few times.
So let's briefly cover what exactly these are.
Node.js is an open source environment for servers,
where JavaScript can be run outside of a browser.
Think about a social media page for instance,
that page is going to contain different content for each different user,
based on their social network.
Node allows for JavaScript to run outside of the browser to gather
the various relevant post for each given user and then send those posts to the browser.
In our case, a node server can be used to handle the data coming in from the MQTT
and FFmpeg servers and then actually render that content for a webpage user interface.
In the upcoming exercise as well as in the project,
you'll be given the main Node servers;
one for the UI and one for the MQTT server.
It will be your job to communicate with them from the Python app.
Note that you can also utilize a more basic front-end
with HTML and CSS for a web page like this.
But these type of front-end skills are outside the scope of this course.
Using these type of servers though,
is closer to a more end-to-end piece for the Internet of Things.
So you've built out your app but what
happens to the information you processed at the edge?
Someone or something probably wants to receive that data.