Outstanding work.
You can now use all the pieces necessary to build
an Edge application as well send its data to a server.
Let's go ahead and take a quick look at my approach.
Back in the classroom Workspace,
we'll first look at how I use MQTT,
as well as sending the output frame with ffserver.
Let's go ahead and look first at what the input and output videos were for this,
just in case something on your side wasn't going to the browser correctly.
Our input video is just a very short video of a car driving down a highway.
However, this could be used in a self-driving car application.
The output video of our network is the semantic mask of the car driving along.
A self-driving car might seem like an odd application of sending data over the internet.
But think about if a car had an accident,
you might want to know data about the steering angle,
the speed, acceleration as well as what it is all
around it as the accident occurred and before it.
So here we are in the app,
and I've made sure that I import MQTT here,
and I've used an alias to shorten it a little bit.
I've also gone ahead and use socket,
which I'll use to actually load the host name and IP address for MQTT.
Note that I've set the port here,
although you won't need to actually check and make sure
the MQTT server is configured on this.
This is the standard but it could be different in different situations.
Above, we'll see that there are different classes that the output uses,
and then right when I start to actually in-fer on video,
before I even load the inference engine in,
I'm going to go ahead and establish my MQTT client and use some of the data above.
Note that this keep-alive interval,
just make sure to check every once in a while
that the connection hasn't been canceled from the other side.
Down below I'm going to go ahead and publish some of
the class information and some data from the speedometer.
I actually just created this for you at just a random speed,
but again it's just another example so you can practice using topics with MQTT.
Below that and outside of the inference request,
I've actually gone ahead and use
system.stdout to write out the output frame and flush it.
At the very bottom,
when everything's done running,
in our case the video's done,
I go ahead and disconnect from our MQTT client.
Now, at this point just because you entered in these two lines for
FFmpeg doesn't actually send that to the FFmpeg server.
You still need to make sure to feed it in when
you run the app itself from the command line.
Let's look at how to run this app within the workspace.
I have a few different terminal windows open.
Note that if you need to open new terminal windows, you can use New,
Terminal, up here in the menu from File,
and you'll be able to open more terminals.
In this case, this application actually needs four terminals open.
Here we have one for the node server related to the MQTT broker server.
This one will handle the UI.
We have another one that will handle FFmpeg,
and the last one will actually run the Python app.
So to start, the node./server.js,
and we should see that our Mosca server
which in this case it's our MQTT server, has started.
Over here, within the UI folder,
we use npm run dev.
This will go ahead and compile web pack,
and it'll take a few seconds here,
but at the end it should tell us that web pack has compiled successfully.
Here we now know that the UI is ready to go.
Next up is FFmpeg,
in this case the ffserver and we're just feeding in our configuration file.
Here we can see that ffserver has started.
Now we can actually run the app.
So again we'll start with actually running the app,
but we need to feed in FFmpeg with the Pipe symbol.
This means that the information coming from our Python script
will get fed to FFmpeg or pipe to it.
Here I'm also just saying that I want to see any warnings that might come out of it.
It's going to be in the format of raw video.
The pixel format is BGR.
This is our video size frame rate
and then this is actually part of our configuration file.
The IP address here's from the configuration file as well as the port
and this is just the file that the ffserver is actually going to pick up from.
Now if I run this, we won't actually see much output over here,
but because we had the MQTT server over here,
we'll be able to see what's getting published.
We'll see that both our classes and speedometer is getting published.
Here in the workspace, you can click on Open app,
and it'll take a second to actually load our image here,
but we'll be able to see that we have our class is counted
and speed coming in as well as the image,
that's our semantic mask output.
Note that this will run a little bit slow and that's just
because semantic segmentation is pretty resource-intensive.
This application of a self-driving car,
you'd probably have a GPU in the car so that you had additional acceleration.
We won't see more on GPUs until later courses,
but this is one potential application where you can
see that you might want to try out different hardware devices.
You've come a long way with your edge skills.
Now, we'll take a step away from all the code and try to use
additional thinking and analytical skills to further build up on your applications.