We're now through the programming parts of this lesson,
and to finish things off,
I want to cover some more discussion-based and analytical topics.
We've talked a lot about optimizing for inference,
and running apps at the edge.
But it's always important to not skip past the accuracy of your edge AI Model.
Lighter, quicker models are helpful for the edge,
and certain optimizations like lower precision that
help with these will have some impact on accuracy.
No amount of skillful post-processing and attempting to extract
useful data from the output will make up for a poor model choice,
or one where too many sacrifices were made for speed.
Of course, it all depends on
the exact application as to how much loss of accuracy is acceptable.
Detecting a pet gain into the trash
likely can handle less accuracy than a self-driving car.
Now, the considerations of speed, size,
and network impacts are still very important for AI at the edge.
Faster models can free up computation for other tests.
They can lead to less power usage,
and allow for the use of cheaper hardware.
Smaller models can also free up memory for other tasks,
or allow for devices with less memory to begin with.
We've also discussed some of the network impacts earlier on.
Especially for remote edge devices,
the power cost of heavy network communication may significantly hamper their use.
Lastly, there can be other differences in Cloud versus edge costs,
other than just network effects.
While potentially being lower up front,
cloud storage and computation costs can add up over time.
As we discussed earlier on,
data sent the cloud could be intercepted along the way.
Although, this does depend on a secure edge device,
which is not always the case for the internet of things.