Throughout the course, we've hit a lot on different use cases for edge applications.
It's important to think on
any additional use cases for a given model or application you build.
These can go far beyond the original training set or intended use.
For example, object detection can be used for so many different things.
If a given model is mainly focused on particular classes along with some post-processing,
there can be very different applications to come from it.
As another example, think of pose detection.
It's useful for video games such as dancing,
motion capture, and tracking movement,
exercise applications, and even health applications,
noting posture or even that something could be
wrong are additional use cases that can be used here.