Before we close out this lesson and the course,
I want to add a final note on considering the needs of your applications end users.
If you're building an app for
certain end users it's very important to consider their needs.
Knowing their needs can inform the various trade offs you
make regarding model decisions such as speed,
size and accuracy as well as what information you send the servers,
security of information etc.
If they have more resources available,
you might go for a higher accuracy but more resource intensive apps.
On end-user with remote low-power devices will likely
have to sacrifice some accuracy for a lighter faster application.
They'll also need some additional considerations about network usage.
This is just to get you thinking.
Building edge applications is about more than just models and code.