To begin this lesson,
we'll look into some of the basics of OpenCV and Open Source Computer Vision library.
OpenCV is an open source library
for various image processing and computer vision techniques.
It runs on a highly optimized C++ backend,
although it's available for use with Python and Java as well.
It's often helpful as part of your overall edge applications.
There are a lot of uses of OpenCV.
In your use case,
you'll largely focus on it's ability to capture and read frames from video streams,
whether a video file,
or active camera stream, or an image.
It also has other pre-processing techniques like converting from
one color space to another which may help in extracting certain features from a frame.
There also plenty of computer vision techniques included,
such as Canny Edge Detection which helps to extract
edges such as the shape of a person from an image.
It also extends even to a suite of different machine
learning classifiers for tasks like face detection.
Here are a few useful OpenCV functions you might want in your edge application.
VideoCapture can read in a video or image and extract a frame from it for processing.
As the name suggests,
resize is used to resize a given frame.
You've seen this a few times before,
cvtColor can convert between different color spaces such as BGR and RGB.
You might remember this from back with
the TensorFlow models that they're usually trained with RGB images,
while OpenCV is going to load frames as BGR.
There was a technique with the model optimizer that would build
a TensorFlow model to appropriately handle BGR.
But if you didn't add that additional argument at the time,
you could use this function to convert each image to RGB,
but that will add a little extra processing time.
Now you've seen cv2.rectangle a little bit before.
This is useful for drawing bounding boxes onto an output image.
cv2.imwrite is also useful for saving down a given image.
Of course, I suggest taking a look at
different OpenCV documentation as well as tutorials if you want to learn a little more.
We'll look specifically at handling input streams with OpenCV next.