In previous lessons you've got everything set up
to perform efficient inference with the OpenVINO toolkit.
But what about actually feeding the input into the Edge application itself?
Being able to efficiently handle video files,
image files or webcam streams is an important part of an Edge application.
If I were to be running the webcam on my MacBook for instance and perform an inference,
a surprisingly large amount of resources get used up simply to use the webcam.
That's why it's useful to utilize the OpenCV functions built for this.
They are about as optimized for general use with input streams as you'll find anywhere.
We saw the cv2.VideoCapture function in the previous video.
This function takes either a zero for
webcam use or the path to the input image or video file.
That's just the first step though.
This capture object must then be opened with Capture.Open,
then you can basically make a loop by checking if Capture.
opened. You can read a frame from it with a Capture.Read function.
This function will actually return two items;
a boolean and the frame.
If the boolean is false,
there is no further frames to read such as if the video's
over so you should go ahead and break out of the loop.
Once there are no more frames left to capture,
there's a couple of extra steps to end the process with OpenCV.
First you'll need to release the capture which will
allow OpenCV to release the captured file or string.
Secondly, you'll likely want to use the cv2Destroy-all-Windows function.
This will make sure any additional windows
such as those use-of-you output frames are closed out.
There's actually one other thing to consider while the stream itself is still capturing,
checking for key presses.
You may want to add a call to cv2.waltkey within
the loop and break the loop if your desired key is pressed.
For instance if the key pressed is 27,
that's the escape key such as control C on your keyboard,
that way you can close the stream midway throughout with a single button.
Otherwise you may get stuck with
an open window that's a bit difficult to close on its own.
Next up you'll get to practice some of these skills
yourself and the exercise on handling input streams