Great work on this exercise.
Now that you've implemented Inputstream handling and a couple other OpenCV techniques,
let's look at my approach.
So here within the app,
this one's a little different than the last view we've done,
I'm only taking in the input file as we actually
won't worry about performing any inference on this video.
All you're going to do is take in an image,
video or webcam, although unfortunately
the webcam option won't be available within the work space,
resize it as noted in the instructions and then you'll
also go ahead and perform canny edge detection on each frame and then write it out.
Let's go through this step-by-step.
First off I decided to create a flag for single images.
This is mainly because how this processed is different whether it's
an image versus a webcam stream or a video.
This is both true when wanting to write to it,
like here I use the CV2.Videowriter to write an output video.
As you'll see below that video writer writes the frame but if the image flag is true,
it's just going to write out a single image file with imwrite.
Back up top, you can see that I check the input.
In my case I decided if you use CAM as
the input that would set it to zero which means the input is webcam.
Otherwise, if it's a JPEG or bitmap file I set the image flag to true.
Here I feed in the input to VideoCapture and note here when I open this,
I switched the arch's that I when it's cam so that instead
of actually being cam it gets switched to zero by the time you get here.
Otherwise, this could also be the video path.
So here if it's not an image we'll create the video writer.
Otherwise, I just set out to none and we don't need to use it further.
From there, I check if the capture's open.
I'll go ahead and read a frame and then I also add in this key press
with CV2 at waitKey so that I can easily cancel out of open CV.
Further on, as in the instructions
and just to give you a little bit more practice with Open CV,
I had you resize the image to 100 by 100 and then perform canny edge detection.
This is with a min value of a 100 and a max value of 200.
Here, again as I mentioned there's a difference with the image flag or without it.
Where either we use imwrite to write out
the output image or otherwise write to our video writer.
Here the key press is checked, and again,
this escape character might be Control-C,
for instance on a Mac where it will break,
and then further out you just need to make sure before you exit
the program that you go ahead and release our video writer,
capture and destroy all windows.
Then here in the terminal,
this one's pretty straightforward to run,
I would just say python app.py and add my input,
and for instance I could use the test video or my blue car,
which are the test images in the directory and see the output.
So now we've shown how to handle input streams.
This is great to be able to handle lots of
different sensory information coming in especially with cameras.
Next up we'll go ahead and start getting into handling the outputs a little further.
You can get a bounding box or some semantic masks,
but what do you actually do with them?