When training neural networks,
a lot of the focus is placed on accuracy,
such as detecting the right bounding boxes and having them placed in the right spot.
But what should you actually do with those bounding boxes
or semantic masks, classes, etc?
What further information can we get from them?
Think of semantic segmentation performed over a road scene for a self-driving car.
The model says there are people to detected.
Should the car always stop?
If they're in the road or a crosswalk, probably so.
But if they're sitting in chairs at a cafe off to the side,
that's probably not incredibly important,
as long as your car keeps to its lane on the road.
How about if you have a pet with a particular affinity for eating trash?
You can ban him from the room where the trash can is,
but he might still ignore the rules when you aren't home.
If you detected your pet near the trash can with your webcam,
perhaps you could play a sound to remind him to stay away.
It's really important to get useful information from your model.
Information from one model can even be further used in an additional model.
Traffic data from one set of days could be used
to predict traffic on another set of days for example,
such as near to a sporting event.
Let's consider some basic logic to extract useful data from the model output.
In the road scene, you could perform
an analysis on what the pedestrian class appears over.
Is it a road or a sidewalk?
Or in this case, it can even be combined with other sensor data.
Is the pedestrian moving toward the road or away from it?
For the pet getting in the trash at
the bounding box for the trash can and the dog overlap at all,
play the warning sound.
For the traffic example,
you'd likely want to count how many bounding boxes there are,
but making sure to only count once for each vehicle until it leaves the screen.
You could also consider which part of the screen they
come from and which part they exit from.
Does the left turn arrow need to last longer near to a big event?
Maybe this might happen if all the cars seem to be heading in that direction.
In an earlier exercise,
you played around a bit with the confidence threshold of bounding box detections.
That's another useful way to extract statistics.
Are you making sure to throw out low confidence predictions?
In the next exercise,
you'll put some of these into action to keep some unfriendly pets apart.