I hope you had some fun with this exercise.
It seems like it's maybe something that could happen in
real life and something you might want to implement at home.
Let's go ahead and walk through what I did in this exercise.
Just to go back over the background of this exercise,
we have three pets at home,
a cat and two dogs.
The cat and one of the dogs get together fine,
but the cat and the second dog always get into fights when they're around each other.
So for this IoT device,
we're going to use a webcam essentially.
In our case, it'll be an input video but check
whether what we see is the cat and dog number 1 together or the cat and dog number 2.
It could also be of course,
that now the pets are on there or only one of the pets or both dogs.
Really, what we're mainly concerned about is
the cat and dog number 1 and the cat and dog number 2.
Now, the model that's used for this is super basic,
it's really only going to put out three classes.
Really what this is, is if you had an object detection model first,
they could tell you the dog breeds and maybe if there's a cat in the image,
and then you process it a little further just to put them into the three categories
of having no pets or the two dogs on screen,
or just one pet.
Another class it's when it's a cat and dog number 1
and another class it's the cat and dog number 2.
Let's check out what the input video for this
was so we can see exactly what we might expect.
Here's the friendly dog and the cat and it's
interspersed with the dog and the cat that are confrontational.
As we go through the video, in fact,
we can see they're fine but near the end,
the dog and the cat that don't like each other are going to get in a fight.
So let's look at our application.
First, we're mainly just going to have to input
the XML file for the model as well as the input file,
although I went ahead and fed it in directly from our exercise.
Then down below, let's look at what I did when it infers on video.
Most of this code is what we've covered in the previous exercises,
so you actually didn't have to do too much with the rest of it.
The main thing I did here is in my assessing the scene function.
You might wonder what exactly this incident flag is that I added and it's
actually so I can track whether there is a current ongoing incident.
What I decided to do was send in the result and a counter,
as well as the incident flag,
and note that my counter here starts at zero and I'm
basically trying to use it for that timestamp, essentially.
I look at this and say,
"Using my result," because the second class or one for 0,
1, and 2 is the one that's the bad combination.
If there's not a currently ongoing incident,
I want to go ahead and get my timestamp which I got from my counter,
and here's 30 for 30 frames per second and I went to log when the incident happened,
and then tell my pets to break it up.
In this case, I go ahead and set the incident flag to true.
This means that the next time around,
I'm not constantly starting up this message
because if I just sit there and keep hitting the same sound again and again,
and again at each of 30 frames per second,
well, the pets probably won't ever get the idea.
The other case is when either there aren't pets
on screen or it's the friendly dog with the cat,
the incident flag is set to false so it can reset.
Let's look at the app in action.
Here, I'll run my app and my model XML file is already here in the directory with me.
So note, it's going to take a few seconds to
run but each time there's an incident in the video,
we'll get out a timestamp and get to see break it up.
So the first one happened at 3.8 seconds and if you time that against the original video,
that's about when the unfriendly dog and the cat appear.
A second incident happens at 10.87 seconds and again,
they get a break it up message.
Note that this is just when the video is playing.
One thing I didn't implement in the app was to actually
check for if the incident has gone on for a long time,
maybe I would want to replay my message,
say once every 10 seconds or something.
In this case, it was just because of how the video
was cut up that it tended to work out that way.
That's it. We saw here that I went ahead and delayed these messages a little bit.
This is good so that we're not constantly sending
information that's just repeating the same thing again and again.
You probably wouldn't constantly want to get alerts at work,
that your pets are having difficulties with each other.
However, in this fashion,
you process the data a little bit and
you make sure you cut down on the amount of data getting sent.
In this case, we saw that we want to keep this a little bit more
lightweight and already understanding this,
will help us a lot going forward.
Coming up, we'll look at MQTT and FFmpeg,
which will help with sending statistics and image frames over the Internet.
Now, that you've looked at how you can process
information and make sure you're not sending too much of it,
both of these methods will be really useful for building your edge applications.