Now, you're able to take an input stream,
perform inference on it,
and extract some additional useful information from the output.
What if you want this information to be available somewhere else?
Going forward from the pet example,
maybe you want to open a webpage or an app on your phone where you can receive
the data both on how many times the cat and the dog got caught in the same room,
as well as even a recording of when that happened.
We'll first look at MQTT,
which is useful for sending small portions of data to servers,
as well as a technique for sending frames of video to a server.
MQTT stands for MQ Telemetry Transport,
where the MQ came from an old IBM product line called IBMMQ for message queues.
Although MQTT itself does not actually use queues.
Now, this doesn't really give a lot away about its usage.
Really, it's useful because it's a lightweight publish-subscribe architecture.
It's designed for resource constrained devices and low bandwidth set-ups.
This is used a lot for Internet of
Things devices or other machine-to-machine communication,
and it's been around since 1999.
Port 1883 is reserved for use with MQTT,
and you'll see us use that with servers later.
On the last slide,
I mentioned the concept of publish-subscribe.
In this architecture, there's a broker or
hub that receives messages published to it by different clients.
Then routes the messages to any client subscribing to those particular messages.
This is managed through the use of what are called topics.
One client publishes to a topic while another client subscribes to that topic.
The broker is going to handle passing the message from
the publishing client on that topic to any subscribers.
These clients don't actually need to know anything about each other,
just the topic that they want to publish or subscribe to.
MQTT is just one example of this and is very lightweight.
While you could publish information such as the counted bounding boxes over MQTT,
you cannot publish a video frame using it.
Publish-subscribe is also used with self-driving cars,
such as with the Robot Operating System or ROS for short,
where a stoplight classifier may publish on one topic with
an intermediate system that determines when to break subscribing to that topic,
and then that system may publish to
another topic that the actual brake system itself subscribes to.