Moving on from the basics of MQTT and publish-subscribe,
I want to show you how to work with MQTT in Python.
There's a useful Python library for working with MQTT called paho-mqtt.
Within, there's a sub library called client,
which as you may guess is how you create
the MQTT client that can publish or subscribe to the broker.
Now, you'll need to know the IP address of the broker as well as setting the port for it.
With those, you can then connect to the client and from
there you can either publish or subscribe to different topics.
Publishing involves feeding in the topic name as well as
a dictionary containing the message that is dumped to JSON.
Subscribing just involves feeding in the topic name to be subscribed to.
At the bottom of the page,
I've linked the documentation for this library.
You can use it to answer the quiz below on
the proper syntax for publishing and subscribing in Python.
You also get to use it in a later exercise for
after we've covered streaming videos to servers as well.
Before we move on,
it's important to remember
your Python MQTT client is actually sending this message to a broker server first.
So if you wanted to view data from your Python app on a web page somewhere,
that web page would actually include code to
subscribe to the server not your Python client.
Later in this lesson,
we'll show you how a Node server can be used to accomplish this.
In fact, in the project you will end up with two nodes servers.
One that acts as the MQTT server and
one that subscribes to that server and actually publishes a web page.
Most of the specifics of that are outside the scope of the course.
So these servers will be given to you to interact with from your Python application.
Next, let's look at streaming video to a server.
The other thing that final Node server will be able to receive.