Sometimes you may still want a video feed to be streamed to server.
Think about if you had a security camera that could detect
a person where they shouldn't be and then send an alert.
That's pretty useful on its own but
then you'd probably still went to view the footage itself.
At the start of the course,
we noted that network communications can be expensive in cost,
bandwidth, and power consumption.
Video streaming consumes a ton of network resources as it
requires a lot of data to be sent over the network, clogging everything up.
Even with high-speed Internet,
multiple users streaming video can cause things to slow down.
As such, it's important to first
consider whether you even need to stream video to a server,
or at least only stream it in certain situations such as
when your Edge AI algorithm has detected a particular event.
Of course there are certainly situations where streaming video is necessary.
The FFmpeg library is named as fast forward mpeg,
meaning it's supposed to be a fast way of handling the mpeg video standard among others.
In our case, we'll use the FF server feature of FFmpeg which similar to
MQTT will actually have an intermediate FFmpeg server that the video frames are sent to.
The final node server that displays a web page will
actually get the video from that FFmpeg server.
There are other ways to handle streaming video as well.
In Python you can also use a flask server to do some similar things.
Although here in this course,
we'll focus on FFmpeg.
You can download FFmpeg from FFmpeg.org.
Using FF server requires a configuration file that we will provide for you.
This configuration file sets the port and IP address of the server
as well as some settings like the ports that are seen
video from and the frame rate of the video.
These settings can also allow it to listen to the system standard out
buffer which is how you can send video frames do it in Python.
With the CISSP Python library,
you can use sys.stdout.buffer.write with
input frame as well as flush it to send the frame to the FF server.
If you have an FFmpeg folder containing the configuration file for the server,
you can then launch the FF server with sudo ffserver-f with a configuration file.
You can do this from the command line.
To actually capture these output frames with FFmpeg they need
to be piped into FFmpeg when the Python script is run.
This is done with the Pipe symbol followed by FFmpeg and then any related arguments.
Some of these could be pixel format,
video size and frame rate etc just like we saw with the configuration file.
So what actually receives the output from the FFmpeg server?
That could be a final node server with the UI or just another server for storage.
Let's go ahead and look at what node is next.