We've mentioned a few times there different optimization techniques at
play with the OpenVINO Toolkit and the supported frameworks.
Let's look at a few of these including quantization, freezing, and fusing.
Back in the first lesson when you downloaded different pre-trained models,
you've downloaded certain precisions of these models.
Quantization is related to this topic of precision or
how many bits are used to represent the weights and biases of the model.
During training, having these very accurate numbers can be helpful,
but it's often the case in the inference that the precision
can be reduced without substantial loss of accuracy.
Quantization is the process of reducing the precision of a model.
With the OpenVINO Toolkit,
I was using default to FP32 or 32-bit floating-point values,
while FP16 and INT8 for
16-bit floating-point and eight-bit integer values are also available.
INT8 is only available in the pre-trained models
as a model optimizer is not able to read that level of precision.
FP16 and INT8 will lose some accuracy,
but the models will be smaller and memory and the compute time is faster.
Therefore, this is a very common method used for running models at the edge.
Freezing in this context is different than what you may
normally think of as freezing in training neural networks.
In training, this usually means freezing
certain layers so that you fine-tune and train on only a subset of layers.
Here, this has been used in contexts of
an entire model and is related to TensorFlow models in particular.
Freezing TensorFlow models will remove
certain operations and metadata only needed for training.
For example, backpropagation only exist for training purposes.
It is not used for inference.
Freezing a TensorFlow model is usually a good idea whether
before performing direct inference or converting with the model optimizer.
Fusion relates to combining multiple layer operations into a single operation.
For example, a batch normalization layer,
activation layer, and convolutional layer could be combined into a single operation.
This can be particularly useful for inference.
The separate operations may occur on separate kernels,
while a fuse operation occurs on a single kernel.
This will then incur less overhead and switching from one kernel to the next.
There are a wide variety of optimization used in the software.
Some depend on a given model or layer such as
the automatic fusion of certain layers like linear operations.
The resonant model in particular also has some of its own optimizations.
Check out the link in the classroom for some more information on this specific cities.
Of course, there are also
the different precision levels you choose when using the model optimizer.
There also certain hardware specific optimizations that can be done,
although those will be covered in the later courses.