You've made it through a ton of OpenVINO Toolkit fundamentals.
Now, it's time to integrate everything into an application.
Coming up, we will be converting a model with the model optimizer,
loading it with the inference engine,
adding any necessary pre-processing steps for the input frame,
making inference requests and performing inference,
and handling and processing the outputs.
Of course, we'll make sure all of this gets built into an application.
That sounds like a lot.
But you actually know how to do all of this already.
I'm throwing in a couple of extra steps that go on
top of just the OpenVINO Toolkit pieces as well.
But we'll go ahead and use some of your inference outputs.
But first, is to add functionality
for different confidence thresholds to determine when to drop
bounding boxes for the output and the other is
adding functionality for different colors of the bounding boxes themselves.
By the end of the exercise,
you've fully integrated the inference engine into the app as
well as having some additional customization available for the apps output.
Good luck and I'll see you back here soon.