Outstanding.
You've really worked in the whole workflow here
to utilize the OpenVINO toolkit for this app.
Since we covered some of the steps before in earlier exercises,
I'm going to mainly focus on the new items here like handling the output,
integration into the app,
and adding that additional functionality and customization through the command line.
You can check out the solution code in
the workspace if you're stuck on any of the other parts.
Once again we're back in the classroom workspace.
Now this one was a little bit more intensive of
an exercise as you had to go through all the various steps we've learned so far.
I'll start out with some of the new things,
starting with the inference Python file,
I'll move it over here so we can see it a little easier.
So the three parts you had to deal with here were to begin asynchronous inference,
wait, as well as extracting the output.
Now you did mostly do the async inference before,
but I just wanted to point it out here again,
if you start async you'll feed in
the request ID because we actually are only feeding in one at a time,
although in real asynchronous you'd want to have that as an input to the function.
The inputs here are
our input blob which was actually extracted up here from our network inputs,
and then you feed in the image.
From there, you need to be able to wait for that request to be complete.
Note that I feed a negative one here,
so that it will actually wait until that is complete and then return
the status code to be zero that we can now extract our output.
This is the first really new part,
you'll see with our executable network,
we again feed in our request ID as zero,
although again you may want to add this as
an argument parameter if you do actually have multiple requests running.
At the end user outputs and the self.output blob which similarly to
our input blob from before we extracted up here by iterating through the outputs.
Now let's go ahead and shift over to the app itself,
I'll start with an app that doesn't have all the customizations added in yet,
so we'll skip this step for now.
Down below of course are
your earlier steps of initializing an inference engine and loading it,
and note here that we have some new code to actually use a video for the first time.
You can pre-process the frame similarly to how you've done before,
here you'll call the async inference function you implemented,
and then check whether the wait function returns zero.
When you do, you can extract the output,
so this is just my function to actually extract
the bounding boxes and draw them back onto their original frame.
Up above, you can see here it's just extracting because it's a one by one to start,
I go down a couple of dimensions to the 100 by
7 and each of these hundreds is a single bounding box.
The confidence is going to be the third item,
as the one before that would actually be the class,
so if we also wanted to output that class you can get that from box one.
Then here I'm just using a default of 0.5 for the confidence,
this is now an area I can see that I'll be able to customize here in a second.
Now I extract out each of the bounding box points and feed them in to create a rectangle.
Here's the color we're going to draw the rectangle in,
and remember because it's BGR for OpenCV,
the 255 here is for red,
so these bounding boxes will be red.
Now let's look at how we would customize this.
Now I'm back with a more customized app,
you can see how I feed this into our ArgumentParser,
so I just added a C description for color and CT description.
I think maybe, I could also consider BC for bounding
box color or something similar as well and then I add these as arguments.
Notice that in my case I added these as optional and I set a default,
so note I'm using a string here and you'll notice
that is just specific to my implementation,
you could potentially feed in the value directly.
Here's my confidence threshold which again I'll set a default of 0.5 to.
Now I noted with my r.c for
color that I was using a string and
that's because I just mapped a dictionary back to these values.
Remember it's BGR, so 255,0,0 will be blue and so on for green and red.
Now if I get an invalid dictionary
key meaning someone gave me a color that I wasn't expecting,
I'm just going to default to blue just like I did up in the ArgumentParser itself.
We're then drawing the boxes,
I'm going to make sure I have the args feeding in,
and this time instead of using 0.5 here,
I feed in the confidence threshold.
Similarly in drawing the rectangle,
I'll feed in the argument color.
Down below, you can also see that I extract
this here and make sure that I convert the color,
which is converting from my string into
the values that will actually have fed into cv2 rectangle.
Then here I also make sure that the confidence threshold is a float,
you could potentially do that in the ArgumentParser itself.
So here I'll go ahead and run my app from the terminal with
my model file which is actually our TensorFlow model we converted earlier,
I'm going to set the bounding box color to green and a confidence threshold of 0.6.
So there you have it, you've fully integrated the inference engine as well
as all the other parts of the OpenVINO toolkit into an edge application.
However, there are some other parts of
edge application that we're still implementing for you.
There's a lot of different communication in such
that still needs to happen for an edge application,
and that's what we're going to cover in the next lesson.