Before we step into the final lesson where we'll focus on some more general edge topics,
let's take a look under the hood of the inference engine.
I noted previously that the inference engine is built and optimized in C++,
although that's specific to the CPU version and
isn't necessarily the same for all the different devices.
These differences under the hood utilize different optimization based on the hardware,
although you are able to work with a shared API to interact with inference engine,
while largely being able to ignore these differences.
So why is the inference engine built in C++ for CPUs?
In fact, many different computer vision in AI frameworks are
built with C++ and have additional Python interfaces.
OpenCV and TensorFlow, for example,
are built primarily in C++,
but many users interact with the libraries in Python.
C++ is faster and more efficient than Python when well implemented.
It also gives the user more direct access to items in memory and such,
and they can be passed between modules more efficiently.
C++ is compiled and optimized ahead of runtime,
whereas Python basically gets read line by line when a script is run.
On the flip side,
Python can make it easier for prototyping and fast fixes.
It's fairly common then to be using the C++ library
for the actual computer vision techniques and inferencing,
but with the actual application sometimes being in Python,
and then interacting with the C++ Library via a Python API.
As I mentioned a bit ago,
the exact optimizations differ by device with the inference engine.
Well, from your end of interacting with the inference engine is mostly the same.
There's actually separate plugins within it for working with each device type.
CPUs, for instance, rely on
the Intel Math Kernel Library for Deep Neural Networks or MKL-DNN.
CPUs also have some extra work to help improve device throughput,
especially for CPUs with higher numbers of cores.
GPUs meanwhile, utilize the Compute Library for Deep Neural Networks or clDNN,
which also uses OpenCL within it.
Using OpenCL introduces a small overhead right when the GPU plugin is loaded,
but it's only a onetime overhead cost.
The GPU plug-in works best with FP16 models over the FP32 models.
Getting to DPU devices like the neural compute stick,
there are additional costs associated with it being a USB device.
It's actually recommended to be processing four inference requests at any given time.
This is in order to hide the cost of data transfer from
the main device to the DPU through the USB.
Later courses, we'll dive into these hardware differences in more detail.