Nice work. With the IR loaded into the inference engine,
we'll soon be able to make inference requests.
Let's go ahead and take a quick look and my approach to this exercise.
So here we are back in the classroom workspace.
Let me go ahead and drag this over so we can view it a little more easily.
To start, I made sure to import the necessary libraries.
I imported OS mainly just so I can use
the name for the XML file towards the binary file for the model.
Then from openvino.inference_engine, I went ahead and imported
the IENetwork and IECore objects we talked about before.
Note that I've added the CPU extension here hard-coded for the workspace.
So you don't need to worry about adding that yourself.
Below, we can notice from the arguments that we just have to
feed in the location of the model XML file and nothing else.
Here, let's walk through the to do from the exercise.
First, to load the inference engine API,
I just use the IECore object,
and I went ahead and name that plugin.
Below, I've got the model binary file path just by using the model
XML file with the OS library I imported
earlier and adding the binary extension at the end.
Then with IENetwork, we want to load the model,
which again is the architecture with the XML and then the weights with the binary file.
Further below, I added the CPU extension.
Now for your own, I'll actually suggests
that even once you've figured out how to use add_extension,
you might try running the code without it.
You'll notice that some of the models actually don't
need the CPU extension that we used here,
but at least one of them will.
As far as supported layers go,
you can use the query_network function we discussed earlier.
This just takes our network,
and then it needs the device name,
which in the workspace is just CPU.
Now we can go ahead and iterate through
the layers and check for which ones are unsupported layers.
This means we can get the layers that are in our network,
which will be dictionary keys,
and compare them to what was in supported_layers.
If this list has anything in it for unsupported layers,
then we'll need to end the program.
Otherwise, the program will crash.
So here, I just went ahead and printed out which layers were
supported so the user can go and look for any necessary extensions,
and noted that they should check for extensions.
After that, I go ahead and exit the program with an error.
Lastly, to load the network into the inference engine,
you can just use the load_network function.
This just needs our network with the CPU.
Since we already know now that there's no unsupported layers,
or else we would have exited,
this function should execute successfully and give us this message.
Let's try this out with one of the models.
So here's my command to go ahead and run my solution,
just Python, the network,
and with my model, which I've gone ahead and moved
our models into this models directory within the workspace,
so it's a little shorter of a path.
We can see we successfully reached the end of the script,
which means that the inference engine successfully loaded our IR model.
Great. Now that we're able to feed in IR to the inference engine,
we'll be able to make inference requests very shortly.