Amazing. You now know how to make inference request to the inference engine.
Let's go ahead and walk through my solution for doing so.
Back in our Workspace,
go ahead and drag over our inference file here, and let's take a look.
Here, there's a few more arguments to use.
We're, again, going to have our model XML file
but we'll also have the location of the image input,
and we'll allow the user to decide whether to use asynchronous or synchronous.
This is just for this application to show the differences between the two,
usually you, as the developer, would decide on this.
Now below, before we get into the exact solution,
I just want to show a little bit about this other code.
We'll once again read in our image and we extract the image shape from there.
We're actually going to use our pre-processing function
we used long ago in the pre-trained models lesson.
Now we can actually iterate through the inputs here.
That's something that we're going to use to feed in to our inference request.
Now here, since we had an argument defending these,
that's how I decide in the code to send
it to either the async inference or synchronous inference.
If it's something other than a or s,
we need to end the program because we don't know what the user actually wants.
Let's first look at my implementation for synchronous inference.
This one is pretty straightforward.
With our executable network,
you just need to use the infer function,
and with our input blob,
we feed in the image.
This is actually going to directly return
the result of the inference so we can return that here.
If we look just at asynchronous inference,
we're going to have the same inputs of
our executable network input blob and image but it's going to handle things differently.
As we mentioned, it starts by starting async.
This will have a request ID.
Here, I just gave it a request ID of zero
because even though we're implementing async here,
we're actually only doing one thing.
It's just our image again with our input to the network named as input blob.
If you had multiple request to make,
you could be feeding in different request IDs.
Then you would refer to these outputs by that ID.
Below, I made a while loop.
It's going to check on the status and wait if the status isn't equal to zero.
If it is, I'm going to wait for a second here.
Now, normally, we're not going to have to actually wait that long.
But if you had a truly complex model,
it could actually be taking longer than that.
Once the status return from the wait function is zero, I'll break the while loop.
There is a difference here.
I'm not returning the exact results here which might seem a little weird.
I did that before with the synchronous function but why not with async.
Well, the difference is to get the output we have to go
a little deeper than just returning the output from,
well, I don't actually see a function here that would return the output.
So while down below,
I'm going to feed out to our test function with an output from each of these.
These outputs are not the same thing.
Now as we move later into the lesson,
you'll actually get to handle this output and extract
the inference request from synchronous and asynchronous.
But we're not going to do that here.
You can take a look into the test code if you want to
find how that's being done but we'll soon hit that in the videos.
Before we leave, I'll go ahead and run the test just to show that it's actually working.
Great. We passed for all six test.
In just a few short lines of code,
we're now able to make inference request to the inference engine,
both synchronously and asynchronously.
Next, let's look at how to actually handle those results.